Linda Paris

6 Park View Court, Alderfield Road, Chorlton, Manchester M21 9JX 07983 502918 lindagparis@gmail.com

PROFILE

I bring 10+ years' successful administration support, HR and project management expertise within the public, private and charitable sectors. Being a competent Personal Assistant, I am also skilled in advice and advocacy, training and IT, adding value with cross-cultural and customer service experience. I confidently remain calm under pressure and am able to appropriately exercise sensitivity and discretion. I am an excellent team worker, communicator and successful problem solver and consider myself to be a respected and trusted manager, co-worker and colleague.

I have travelled extensively, published written articles and am a healthy living enthusiast. In the periods between paid employment I have furthered my professional training and development and have spent time travelling and volunteering for various organisations both in the UK and overseas.

CAREER HISTORY

PA & Office Manager Rendall & Rittner Limited

January 2018 - September 2019

My responsibilities included and were not limited to:

- Managing the diaries of the North Area Leadership Team.
- Assisting the North Area Director.
- Organising meetings, travel and events.
- Preparing packs for meetings, attending and taking minutes.
- Overseeing the Health and Safety in the office.
- Monitoring and ordering stationery and kitchen supplies.
- Liaising with suppliers and contractors and maintaining facilities management for the office.
- Assisting with operational tasks as and when required.

More recently I co facilitated an office relocation to new premises.

I was also part of the company's wellbeing focus group and organised and facilitated wellbeing events in the north area office.

Personal Assistant to the Directors

Sherlock Homes Properties Ltd

January 2015 - January 2018

My principle role was to support the directors with the managerial and operational functions of the business. Responsibilities include and are not limited to:

- Being the initial point of contact for the Managing Director when and responding to email enquiries on the director's behalf.
- Produce letters, reports and draft responses on behalf of the director for review.
- Carry out aspects of accounting, bank reconciliation and paying invoices.
- Credit control and customer relations.
- · Preparing papers for litigation.
- · Compliance.
- The administration and facilitation of HR processes and procedures.
- Managing a diary and arranging meetings and events.
- Office management.
- My role also includes various tasks pertaining to all aspects of property management as and when required, within given deadlines.

Radio Host

ALL FM 96.9 Manchester

August 2014 - January 2015

I co-hosted a radio show at a local community radio station which involved all aspects of technical production.

Sales Assistant

Barbakan Delicatessen & Bakery

October 2012 - September 2014

I worked as part of the front-line team undertaking varied tasks to maximise the smooth operation of a busy local Delicatessen and Bakery.

Volunteer Mentor

December 2011 - October 2012

As part of a women's personal development network I provided mentoring and support on a voluntary basis. I also completed further professional training.

Employment Law Consultant Peninsular Business Services

May - November 2011

I coached clients on pragmatic and effective methods for dealing with human resource issues in line with the legal framework. My primary role involved delivering tailored legal advice to small businesses across the UK in line with client's business objectives.

Senior Advisor | Advice Service Manager | Debt Caseworker Citizens Advice - Various locations in the North West

September 2006 - April 2011

Over a period of 5 years I worked in various roles within Citizens Advice Bureaux in the North West to include and not limited to:

- Provided face to face specialist debt advice and successfully negotiating repayment plans for service users.
- Coached and tutored clients on more sustainable money management.
- Interpreted complex legal advice and all aspects of welfare rights issues including housing, consumer, employment, welfare benefits and immigration.
- Successfully developed, managed and introduced new initiatives.
- Monitored and developed the quality of advice.
- Managed, mentored and supported a team of volunteer and paid staff.
- Developed working relationships with a variety of stakeholders.
- Promoted equal opportunities and cross-cultural inclusion.
- Carried out all associated administration tasks to include the preparation of letters and various documents for the senior management team, staff, volunteers and service users.

Business Administrator Laughing Buddha Life Centre

December 2005 - July 2006

My primary role was to promote, facilitate and co-host self-development events and I took the lead in setting up and maintaining efficient and effective administrative systems. I was also the first point of contact for visitors and users of the venue.

Yoga Teacher

Sivananda Yoga Ashram Retreat, Bahamas

December 2004 - May 2005

I prepared and delivered a core training programme as part of the Ashram experience to meet varying levels of student experience.

Lay Advocate and Debt Advisor Denbighshire (North) Citizens Advice

January 2000 - November 2004

I co-developed and managed a successful county court representation and debt advice service, to achieve the following:

- Developed working relationships with stakeholders to include County Court personnel, the local authority and social housing providers.
- Coached and tutored clients on more sustainable and intelligent money management.
- Trained volunteer advisors on debt advice processes and related matters.
- Successfully prevented homelessness to 98% clients represented.
- Performed all associated administrative tasks.
- Prepared a funding application and successfully secured an additional 3 years funding for the project.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

- Preparing To Teach in the Lifelong Learning Sector (PTLLS)
- Certificate in Management Institute of Management
- CENTRA Counselling Skills Level 2
- RSA Levels 1-3 Typewriting and Word Processing
- BTEC Higher National Diploma Level 5
- Yoga Alliance Certificate Yoga Instructor Sivananda Vedanta